today we're going to use Peruvian
chocolate to make a black forest flavor
ice cream we got everything weighed out
ready to go so let's just get on and do
[Music]
it I love chocolate ice cream it's my
favorite flavor I like making chocolate
ice cream with different chocolates from
around the world I've done chocolate
with other South
American I've done chocolate ice cream
with other
South American chocolate before it is
time to try another one this came from
the UK this is it's got a label straight
at the top of it which doesn't help
matters it's come from willly cacal
great name um he did a TV program he was
down in Southwest he is down in the
southwest of the UK down where I used to
live and he was he did a TV show where
he sold himself as the Willie Wonka of
chocolate it's excellent quality I don't
know if you can get it at other parts of
the world but if you can and you do find
Wily's cacao it is excellent so we've
got a block here this is a cooking block
so it's 100% caca it's it's
185 G this this thing it's two tablets
inside like so two tablets
all right it's got the Willies caca
thing probably can't see it I'll put a
picture up on the screen it's designed
to be
used in cooking and ice cream and
chocolates and savory dishes as well
it's beautiful stuff so we're going to
make a Black Forest Ice Cream it's quite
a unique recipe this one let's get our
parts measured out that we don't already
we're going to start with our milk which
is 705 G we are going to
add 400 G of this is heavy cream
36% see all that lumps of cream coming
out there amazing
stuff G oh
3.99 keep that bold use that for
something else I've already measured out
our sugars and our other ingredients so
in here I have 160 g of sugar and and 2
G of my stabilizer blend if you only use
a single stabilizer like G gum or
something that is fine you might want to
drop it down a little bit and in here we
have 120 g of dextrose 1 G of pink
Himalayan salt so we are going
to get a tiny whisk mix our stabilizer
into our sugar do that to break up any
lumps of stabilizer and it also helps it
dissolve in our
liquid like so so we can do that with a
dexr and salt but it doesn't make any
difference like
so what we can do now is get our sugars
into our
Dairy like
so and let's get that on the hob start
it warming up whilst that's doing
that we can get our chocolate and cut
this up it's a big chunk of chocolate
this so we need to
get it chopped up otherwise we're going
to burn
everything in the
pan so with our Dairy warming up we need
to get this to 85c 185f anyway cuz we're
using a stabilizer that is heat
processed so we're going to start to add
in our
[Music]
chocolate and bring this up to
temperature so as we start to get up to
temperature
82 we're getting really close now keep
an eye on it you it will start quite
bitty and grainy and you'll think this
will never come together but once it
reaches 60 Cade all the chocolate and
the Coco fat starts to dissolve and we
get this super decadent kind of mix
going on here so we're just going to
keep stirring this for another couple of
minutes until we get up to our 85 we're
at 86 so we're all good we can turn the
heat off and take that
off so as normal you're going to get
this completely chilled down in the
fridge at least 4 hours please we need
that flavor to develop take it out give
it a little stir if it needs it and then
pop it in your ice cream machine look
how velvety smooth this chocolate ice
cream base is honestly this Peruvian
chocolate is out of this world you don't
have to use Peruvian chocolate you can
just use any chocolate but it needs to
be strong 100% so for our Cherry syrup
we're going to use this fabri amarina
wild cherry syrup it's loaded with sugar
but it's for culinary use so it's not
for using your coffee we're going to
take about 100 G of that syrup and 1
teaspoon of sugar with half a teaspoon
of gagum we're going to thicken this
syrup up so that it's a really nice
consistency stir that sugar and the gum
together and stir it into your
syrup combine those really well with a
little tiny whisk and actually this
benefits from sitting in the
refrigerator for a couple coup of hours
if you don't put it in the refrigerator
it works perfectly so we're going to
carry on and get our additional
chocolate chopped up we're using a 70%
South African chocolate actually this
one is and in the last couple of minutes
of your churn pop it in your machine and
so it's can get fully Incorporated and
when you're finally ready dish it up
into your container do one scoop and
then a really good spoonful of your
cherry syrup and continue that process
until your tub is completely full and
then pop it in the freezer to harden off
completely it's been I think 24 hours
now beautiful color I can feel the side
of the tub this is a perfect scooping
texture let's have a look there we go
Scoops perfectly this has not been taken
out of the freezer ahead of time you
know I don't like doing that you see the
little Flex that cherry syrup come
through the little pieces of that South
African chocolate coming through as well
oh this is good let's zoom in and we're
going to decorate that with some of our
thickened amarina Cherry syrup and we're
done there we go our black Peruvian
Black Forest ice cream with Rich
Cherry syrup the it's important to use a
strong chocolate for this this peren
chocolate is really strong and it's
slightly bitter
and that's important cuz we want that to
cut through with a super sweet cherry
syrup and that 70% South African
chocolate add in there let's try this I
am excited to try this
one I think this is one of my favorite
chocolate ice creams I've ever
made the slight bitterness of that
chocolate base cut through the ultra
Sweet Cherry syrup and those those
balanced chocolate chips throughout this
is
impeccable by thickening the Cherry
syrup you get this layer that doesn't
just disappear in your ice cream put it
in the refrigerator it will go even
thicker and that Gua gum we're just
using that Gua gum to thicken that up
that is incredible stuff fabri syrups
are very very good quality syrups uh
this is 1.3 kilo
bottle it's it's like 80% sugar this
stuff this is for professional use you
can buy it
online um you can buy on Amazon Etc but
you wouldn't use this in coffee this is
for other things this is for
flavoring professional grade food such
as ice cream and gelata it's expensive
you're probably not going to use a lot
of it but you don't have to use this you
can use any syrup that you want but
obviously this is a black forest ice
cream so needs to be
Cherry you know I love chocolate ice
cream it's my
favorite this is
there
man that's
good not much else to say one of the
best chocolate ice creams I've ever
eaten hi to all the new subscribers got
loads coming on board recently there's a
lot of information
for this channel PR grade ice cream made
at home using stabilizers if you want to
how to balance sugar levels how to
balance fat levels different ice cream
gelato sawway we're going to do sherbets
all this kind of thing something to show
you coming up
soon
layered ninja creamy we've got actually
this chocolate ice cream base in here
with layers of flavored alcohol so if
you're interested in knowing how I do
that make sure to like And
subscribe I will see you next time and
I'm going to eat all of this ice cream
because I can
[Music]